I am a Southern California Native being born and Raised in Redlands. I have always loved Utah and decided to live here after I finished Automotive school. I have been an automotive technician for Mercedes Benz for 3 years and have decided it is time to move on in my career.

My journey with Web Development is one of passion and determination. As a child watching Tron and other tech centered films I was amazed by what was possible. I knew at that time that I wanted to learn the skills to do anything with a computer.

In my free time I enjoy hiking, mountain biking, gaming, and managing my personal financial portfolio.

"Only those that can see the invisible, can do the impossible"

Work History

2017-05 -Current

Automotive Technician

Mercedes-Benz Of Draper, Draper, UT

- Maintained fleet vehicles in good working order by following preventive and corrective maintenance schedules according to OEM.
- Inspected damaged vehicles to estimate repair labor cost and required parts expense.
- Broke down complex mechanical information into simpler parts for individuals with little or no understanding of system operations.
- Worked on Mercedes-Benz vehicles to repair engines, transmissions and electrical systems.
- Repaired brake, exhaust, electrical and other systems for all automotive brands.

2012-11 -2014-11

Volunteer Missionary

The Church Of Jesus Christ Of Latter-Day Saints, Vancouver, Canada

- Volunteer representative of the church engaged variously in proselytizing, church service, humanitarian aid, and community service.
- De-escalated and resolved conflicts between local peoples and missionary representatives.
- Trained 2 new missionaries on effectively sharing religious beliefs in local community.

Nicolaus Thomas

Full Stack Web Developer

Contact

Address

3557 S 1100 E

Millcreek, Salt Lake, 84106

Phone

9094356855

E-mail

thomascustoms715@gmail.c

WWW

https://modernviking.github.io /NicksCodingWorld/

LinkedIn

https://modernviking.github.io /NicksCodingWorld/

Skills

Troubleshooting and debugging

Very Good

MySQL

Good

Project management

Good

Teamwork

Very Good

2012-10

Redlands Unified School District, Redlands, CA

- Maintenance of school grounds
- Installation of computer equipment, maintenance of technical devices
- Jack of all trades.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: 2019-11 -2020-05 **Full Stack Web Development**

University of Utah - Sandy, UT

2017-01 -Some College (No Degree): Automotive 2017-04 **Technology**

Mercedes Benz DRIVE - Long Beach, CA

Automotive Technology Certificate: 2015-08 -2016-11

Automotive Technology

Universal Technical Institute of California Inc - Rancho

Cucamonga, CA

High School Diploma 2007-08 -

2011-06 Redlands Senior High School - Redlands, CA

Accomplishments

- Moderate to advanced skill with Microsoft Office
- Typing skill 42 words per minute
- 10 Key skill 70 keystrokes per minute
- Salt Lake County Emissions Inspector License
- MVAC Technician Certification, EPA section 609

Interests

Managing personal investment portfolio

Tracking personal finances and 401K

Languages HTML Superior MySQL Advanced **CSS** Superior **JavaScript** Intermediate Bulma Advanced Bootstrap Intermediate Git Superior **Express** Intermediate Node.js

Intermediate